[ Radio chatter ]
[ 收音机嘎吱嘎吱 ]
[ Squeaks ]
[ 尖叫声 ]
[ Whirring ]
[ 风扇呼呼旋转 ]
Aah!
啊!（￣ε(#￣)
Sorry about that.
我很抱歉
These things are a little tricky to fly.
这些东西 飞起来挺棘手的
Yeah, well, I swear, with a slightly larger one,
对啊 我觉得 如果操纵着大一些的飞行器
you could do some genuine damage, like,
你可以造成一些 有效伤害
maybe even kill somebody.
甚至可能把一个人干掉
Wait a minute...
等等……
[ Muttering ]
[ 仔细想了想 ]
Let's start the show.
让我们开始节目吧
-- Captions by vitac --  www.Vitac.Com
captions paid for by Discovery Communications
[ whirring ]
I'm guess this story's about drones.
我猜这个故事是关于 无人机的
It is, in fact, we have two awesome flying stories
是的 但实际上这一集中我们有 两个棒棒哒的
in this episode.
关于飞行器的流言
One of them is about these guys.
其中一个是关于 这些家伙
But first up, we have a totally amazing story.
但是首先我们 要讲一个精彩的故事
Let me ask you,
我问你啊
do the words "Dragon Lady" mean anything to you?
蛟龙夫人对你来说意味着什么
I don't wanna talk about it.
我不想谈这个
Okay, I think, we're probably thinking of different things.
哦尅 我们可能想到不同的方面去了
'Cause "Dragon Lady" is, in fact, the nickname
因为蛟龙夫人
for the legendary high-altitude single-seater
其实是灯塔国空军
u-2 reconnaissance plane in use by the air force
在50年代对传奇般的高空侦察机
since the late '50s.
U-2的昵称
[ Radio chatter ]
[ 收音机嘎吱嘎吱 ]
Okay, what about it?
行吧 流言是关于什么的
[ Radio chatter ]
[ 收音机嘎吱嘎吱 ]
Well, there is a myth that the u-2 plane
嗯 流言表示
is the toughest plane to fly and to land
U-2侦察机是所有飞机中
of any other plane.
最难操纵起降的飞机
[ Man speaking indistinctly  over radio ]
[ 广播中传来  坚定的声音 ]
And I think we should take a close look at that.
我觉得我们应该近距离看看他
The air force isn't gonna let us
美国空军是绝对不会 让我们
get anywhere near something like that.
接近这么个玩意儿的
C1, 34.8, 34.8.
对讲机： C1, 34.8, 34.8.
I thought the same thing, but amazingly,
我一开始也是这么想的 但是奇迹般的是
they have agreed to let you and I have a close-up,
他们允许了 你和我
first-person look at their u-2 program,
亲自 参观他们的U-2项目
and see just how tough those planes are to operate.
去看看这些 飞机操作是有多难
Oh!
饿啊
Cool. What are we waitin' for?
酷 那我们还等什么呢
I haven't the slightest idea. Let's do this.
没什么可等的了 让我们干♂吧
[ Imitates airplane roaring ]
[ 模仿飞机引擎咆哮 ]
It takes off straight up
它笔♂直得升起来了
and looks something like a jet-propelled four poster.
看起来像喷气推进的四柱架子床
The history of aviation
航空的历史
is littered with oxymoronic aerodynamics,
被逆向空气动力学
finicky flyers, and design duds.
挑剔的飞行员和糟糕的设计再次推动
So is it possible that one of the most long-lived
所以这在世时间最长的
and high-valued U.S. air force vehicles
价值最高的 美国空军飞行工具
is also the toughest to fly?
同时也是最难操纵的？
To open this investigation, there's only one destination.
为开展这个调查 我们该去只有那个地方
[ Radio chatter ]
[ Plane engine roaring ]
Well, when you've got questions about the u-2 plane,
我们已经得到那些 有关U-2的疑问
they will get answered here.
他们将在这里得到一一解答
I'm standing at the home of the u-2 program.
我现在正站在U-2项目的研发地
This is where the planes are serviced.
这里就是这些飞机被提供服♂务的地方
This is where the pilots train
这里是飞行员训练的地方
before flying to every corner of the globe to do their jobs.
在飞到全球各个角落去执行他们的任务之前
We should totally be able
我们必须能够
to get to the bottom of this myth here,
在这里找出流言的真相
and we might even get to fly it.
我们甚至要登上飞机飞行
To begin to understand just how hard it is
为了开始弄懂要完成
to manage this marvel of aviation engineering...
这个奇迹般的航空器有多难
Well, Adam, Jamie,
亚当 杰米
this is the infamous and venerable u-2 Dragon Lady.
这就是声名狼藉却又庄严的U-2蛟龙夫人
...Major Bartholomew, who has more u-2 flying hours
有着比任何空军飞行员
than any air force pilot in history,
都久的U-2飞行经历的巴塞洛缪少校
runs the guys through the specs.
将按照规范训练亚当和杰米
The original design dates from the mid-'50s,
最初设计始于50年代
Bartholomew: Single engine, high-altitude, long wingspan,
Bartholomew: 单发引擎, 高空飞行, 超长翼展
lots of thrust, lots of lift.
超强推力, 超大抬升力
We can take a heavy payload up to a great altitude
我们可以携带很重的荷载到一个很高的高度
and loiter for a long time.
然后续航很久
The challenges this aircraft presents its pilots
这架飞行器带给飞行员的挑战
are numerous and significant.
众多且意义重大
But all the fuel is kept in the wing.
但是所有的燃料都装在机翼中
First up, the plane can't even support
首先 飞机在起飞时并不能支持住
its own massive wingspan when it's taking off.
他重量巨大的机翼
Bartholomew: When the wing develops lift,
Bartholomew: 当机翼即将提升
the pogo falls away.
机翼下方的辅助轮将脱落
Next, recon missions can be lengthy
然后侦察任务将是漫长的
and are carried out at very high altitudes
并且将在一个非常高的高度执行
which requires complex pressure suit technologies
这需要复杂的增压服科技
and extreme safety features.
和极端情况下的安全保障功能
Everything is so thin and so light
所有的东西都是这么薄这么轻
and just strong enough.
却又十分坚固
And then, there's the landing.
最关键的是降落
It has quite a heavy footprint,
它的降落十分猛烈
because there's just the one main gear carrying all the load.
以为只有一个主要的起落架承载所有的重
6, 5, 4...
The wheels are along the center line of the fuselage.
轮子沿着机身的中心线分布
So it's like trying to land a bicycle.
所以它看起来就像降落一辆自行车
When the airplane does tip over,
当机身倾向一侧
these skids protect the wingtip.
这些制动垫料将会保护翼梢
And we'll see later when on approach,
我们之后将看到 即使是接近之后
the pilot can't even see the runway.
飞行员也无法看到跑道
3...2...
Yes, we got it down by a pilot in a chase car.
我们通过另一名驾驶员驾驶追逐车辆来解决这个问题
Two hold at 1 inches.
So far, it's looking pretty good for the myth.
目前来看 流言的情况不错
It's an impressive check list
这是个令人影响深刻的
of piloting challenges, but where next?
对飞行员有着挑战的核对表 但是接下来呢
Well, we need to get a look at this baby in action.
我们必须亲自看一看这个好东西
To that end, Jamie and I have been given the go-ahead
为了那个目的 杰米和我已经 被放行
to hitch a ride to the edge of space.
去搭一趟 到宇宙边缘的顺风车
And we will now embark on a week-long training program.
接下来我们将着手于为期一个礼拜的训练项目
Yep, it takes a week just to learn how to be a passenger.
是的我们将用一礼拜的时间学习如何成为一名乘客
The problem is, there is only room for one of us.
问题是, 只有一人份的空间供我们中的一个人进去
[ Air hissing ] Whoa!
[ Air hissing ] WOW!
[ Laughs ]
[ 蛤蛤蛤 ]
Please, please, please, let it be me!
求你了x3让我进♂去吧
So the next story is deadly drones?
所以下一个故事是致命无人机？
Indeed, it is.
是 就是 确实是
If the press is to be believed,
drones are totally in our future delivering our packages
无人机将在未来运送我们的包裹
and maybe even our pizzas.
甚至是我们的披萨
But there are those who think that they are a deadly danger
但是有些人认为它们是 致命的危险
hiding in plain sight.
潜在的 一目了然
That a simple gust of wind could send a drone into you
无人机可能将在一阵狂风中袭击你
and the propellers could... [ Blows air ]
然后螺旋桨将……咻
Slice your throat and kill you.
切断你的喉咙杀了你
That sounds like it's custom-made for us.
这听起来像 他是为我们定制的
That's exactly what I was thinking.
这正是我所想的
Let's get to testing.
让我们去测试吧
But testing the myth with what?
但是用什么测试这个流言呢
First up, Adam and Jamie take a tour
首先 亚当和杰米全方位的浏览了一下
of the full-range of drone technology,
无人机技术
starting with the super size.
从巨大的尺寸开始
Allow me to introduce
让我介绍一下
our high-tech custom-built camera platform.
我们的定制摄像平台
It's got 8 motors totaling 2,800 watts of power,
它有八个电动机和2800W的动力
it carries a self-stabilized high-definition 3-pound camera.
它携带着自稳定高解析3磅重相机
[ Loud voice ] Pretty cool, huh? [ Loud whirring ]
[ Loud voice ] 超酷 不是吗? [ Loud whirring ]
And at the other end of the scale...
然后在模型的另一边...
This is your basic consumer-level multi-roter.
这是基础消费级别的四轴飞行器
It's on the small side,
他麻雀虽小
but it has all the features that the large ones do --
却五脏俱全
propellers, motors --
螺旋桨 电机……
[ Laughs ]
[ 蛤蛤蛤 ]
Well, as in any new technology, there can be casualties.
任何科技都有它的受害者
But as per the myth,
但是作为流言的一部分
would one of those causalities ever be human?
人类将会成为它的受害者吗
Could a drone really be deadly?
无人机真的可能致命吗
To begin their quest in earnest, it's back to the shop,
为认真开始他们的探索 需要回到工作室
where Adam has two mid-range models
这里 亚当有两个中规模的模型
most likely to be used in a commercial delivery.
最可能用于商业快递
On the left here is
左边的这个是
a fly-it-right-out-of-the-box small model.
即时飞出盒子的小模型
Slightly larger is an intermediate kit-level model,
大一点的是中级的模型
which comes with all the pieces you need to fly.
有着一切你想要飞行的部件
You just have to assemble them.
你只要组装起他们
This one's apparently ready to fly,
这一个已经准备好飞行了
so I'm gonna give it a shot, see how easy it actually is.
所以我将试一试这实际上有多容易飞
Aah, aah, aah!
Really easy to fly. [ Laughs ]
非常容易飞行
While the damage done so far is enlightening...
当前造成的损伤是非常启蒙性的
Aah, aah, aah! A proof of concept is required.
Aah, aah, aah! 观念的证据是很需要的
Ew, it dripped juice on me!
恶 他滴下妹汁在我身上
To find out if a multi-roter propeller
为了搞明白一个普通螺旋桨
could ever cause a flesh wound,
也能造成一条新鲜的伤口
Adam and Jamie have a standard-size blade
亚当和杰米将一条标准尺寸的叶片
spinning at flight speed on a stick...
装在棍子上以飞行时的速度旋转
And a chicken.
然后一只鸡
I think today's lesson is gonna be fairly self-explanatory.
今天的教训是肯定是不解自明的
Whenever you're ready, sir.
随时待命 Sir
[ Blade whirring ]
Yeah! There we go!
液~要来咯
Yeah!
液~
Check that out.
快看看
That right there, my friends, that's an injury.
看就在那里 我的朋友 那里有一个伤口
But let's face it,
让我们来面对一下
we're not just talking about an injury,
我们不仅仅在讨论伤口
we're talking about lethality.
我们在讨论毁灭性的伤害
Which means we're really talking about this vein right here,
这意味着我们确实在讨论这条静脉
the jugular, yeah.
这条颈静脉
I think if we're gonna continue testing,
我觉得如果我们继续试验
we need to make a neck as a testing platform
我们需要制作一个脖子当做试验平台
that we can run our multi-roters into.
我们能够伸进我们的螺旋桨
Coming up on "Mythbusters"...
接下来 在流言终结者
Can someone get me a band-aid?
谁能给我搞一条邦迪®创可贴
Adam's up to his neck
亚当正将脖子伸向
in the gory story of a deadly drone.
致命无人机的血腥故事
And...
还有……
Bail out, bail out, bail out.
跳伞！跳伞！跳伞！
...The guys prepare for the flight of a lifetime.
...大家正在准备有生之年的飞行
Complex and terrifying.
又复杂又吓人
Could a drone delivery ever be deadly?
无人机运输会致命吗？
Aah!
Adam and Jamie have a promising proof of concept.
Adam and Jamie已经准备好了证明
Yeah! There we go.
液~来吧
Now, to cut a little deeper.
现在 切深一点
Now if we're going to be testing whether one of these
既然我们要证明其中一个
can slice through one of these, we're gonna need one of each.
可以切进另外一个 我们需要各一个
And these are easy to buy at the store.
这是很容易在商店买到的
But these -- well, they're a little harder to come by.
但是这些就不是那么容易搞定了
We're gonna have to make our own.
我们要自己制作一个
And to do that, I'm gonna use a lot of this...
为了做到这个 我要用很多很多的这个
And this guy right here.
和这个东西
And it's going to spurt blood if it actually gets cut.
如果他被切断 将喷出血
[ Whispers ] It's gonna be awesome.
这将会很精彩
Yep, Adam's manufacturing
液噗 亚当制造
a mortal mannequin that will react accurately to an impact.
The basic gist of what I'm gonna be doing
我将要做的基本要点就是
is casting a neck out of ballistics gelatin.
是铸造一个脖子 用弹道明胶.
How tall is this neck? Who were these men?
这脖子多高 这些人是谁
With holes in it that I can fill with "blood" that will be blue
因为有管子在里面所以我可以灌入蓝色的血液
for televisual purposes.
为了视觉体验
It needs to be really close to the edge of the skin.
这需要很靠近表皮
So I'm gonna effectively mold those veins
所以我将有效地铸造这些静脉
using these brass rods in here.
运用这些黄铜棒材
It's sort of like thinking inside out and backwards.
有点像想内想外
With the negative mold of the blood vessels in place,
随着模具和血管的就位
it's time to prepare the fake flesh.
是时候来制作假肉了
As Jamie and I have discovered, this stuff reacts to a bullet
杰米和我发现 这东西和子弹发生的反应
similar to human flesh,
很像人体和子弹所发生的反应
but to get the tenacity of skin and muscle,
但为了得到皮肤和肌肉的韧性
we need to add this fiberglass filler to the ballistics gel
我们需要把这个玻璃纤维填料添加到弹道凝胶里
as we're casting it into my mold.
当我们在铸造模具时
Oh, beauty!
Oh, 真漂亮!
Oh, I'm very pleased with how this is going so far,
Oh 到目前为止 我对这一切表示很高兴
based on nothing.
不基于任何事情
Once set, it's simply a case of easing
设置好了以后 就是一段短暂的缓解
the fleshy throat free of the mold.
新鲜的喉咙从模具中取出
Almost, come on!
就要出♂来了！
[ Bleep ] [ Bleep ]
[ Bleep ]
[ Groaning ]
That's it. All right. Thank you.
好了就是这样 谢谢
Then, Adam plums the system with blue blood...
然后亚当将蓝色的血加入到系统中
Nice!
...And tests his anatomically accurate jugular.
.然后测试他那在解剖学上完全正确的静脉模型
It's at the right depth behind the flesh.
他就在皮下正确的深度
That is a bleeding neck.
Narrator:...And requires the same force to slice.
以及需要正确大小的力来切割
All right, could someone get me a band-aid?
好了 谁能给我个邦迪创可贴
Allow me to introduce you to...
让我给你介绍一下
Yeah, rolls right off the tongue.
已经介绍的很顺口了
It is basically a rig for bleeding
这基本上就是个用来流血的装置
when it senses a lethal injury.
当是致死的伤口
Now, I have more than two veins in this rig,
这套系统现在有不止两条静脉
even though we have only two in our neck,
即使我们喉咙只有两条
because we can test multiple times
这样我们就可以测试好几次
just by turning the neck.
只要通过旋转脖子
Yeah, it's, like, that versatile.
液 就像是多功能的工具
So we can test as much as we want
我们想测试几次就测试几次
and watch bursting blue bl-- blue blood,
还能看蓝色的血液喷出
blue blood fly out of the veins. I'm gonna stop talking now.
蓝色的血液从静脉喷出 我要闭嘴了
But before Adam's blue blood dummy
但是在亚当的蓝血假人
is deployed in the drone firing line...
被放置在无人机的杀伤范围之下前
It's back to beale air force base
让我们回到比尔空军基地
to tackle the myth that the u-2
来测试u-2是否是
is the world's toughest plane to pilot.
世界上最难驾驶的飞机
[ Roaring ]
Welcome to altitude, physiology,
欢迎来到高海拔生理学
and full pressure suit orientation.
和增压服操作指南
Adam and Jamie are both in training
亚当和杰米都在为了在飞机上测试流言
for an in-flight investigation.
而刻苦训练
One will fly. One will be on standby.
一个人会上天  一个人会留下待命
Pop your helmet off just like that.
像这样打开你的头盔
And they're starting
他们从几个
with several not-so-brief briefings...
不是很简洁的简介开始
You're gonna have a suit controller like this.
泥萌会用到一个像这样的增压服控制器
...About the safety equipment...
关于安全装备
It acts as a backup pressurization system.
这是一个备份增压系统
...And emergency procedures.
Narrator:以及紧急程序
We're gonna teach you
我们会教你们
how to parachute safely to the ground.
如何安全地伞降
These are no minute-long
这可不是几分钟长的
demonstrations from a flight attendant.
空姐的安全示范
Primarily, it's to prevent decompression sickness.
首先它可以用来防止减压病的出现
And a clear indication of the enormity of the endeavor.
If you lose cabin pressure, the suit would inflate...
如果你的机舱失压 增压服会膨胀起来
If you are unconscious, there are inflaters inside...
如果你失去了知觉 内部的充气
During this time, your visor is gonna freeze over.
这段时间内你的面罩会被冰覆盖
You will not be able to see...
你看不到
So if you have to cut yourself down from something.
所以如果你不得不割断绳索来脱离
Now, we're nowhere near getting into one of these planes yet,
虽然我们现在还无法亲身飞行
but already we've got all this stuff
但我们已经学会了所有
that we have to know how to deal with.
必须知道的解决方法
The good news is you have an ejection seat.
好消息是你有一个紧急弹射座椅
The bad news is you actually have to
坏消息是 你必须
pull your own ejection handle to get out of the aircraft.
拉动自己座位上的紧急弹射手柄来离开飞机
Even something like peeing, uh,
即使是嘘嘘这样的事情，呃
it seems like it's kind of a complicated ordeal.
也像是困难重重的考验
Push down, lock it to the side, and you can begin
向下拉，往旁边锁死，然后你就可以开始
your slow, controlled urination.
小心♂翼翼地嘘嘘了
I don't -- I don't think that I wanna -- I don't wanna
我……我不觉得……我不想
be pushing or pulling buttons
在不知道它们作用的情况下
without really knowing exactly what they do.
对着一堆按钮按来按去
So it's gonna take a little practice.
所以这需要一点小小的练习
So why all of this complex equipment?
所以这些复杂的设备有什么卵用？
Why is the u-2 program, the only program besides NASA...
为什么u-2计划是除了NASA
Absolutely unreal.
“你特么的在逗我”
...And the space program
Adam:和太空计划之外
that utilizes a full pressure suit?
唯一使用增压服的地方
The primary purpose of wearing this full pressure suit
穿增压服的主要目的是
is to prevent hypoxia.
防止缺氧
Well, one is, of course,
呃，其中之一，当然
because it flies higher than any other normal airplane
因为u-2的飞行高度远高于其他任何飞机
into what they call the space equivalent zone
进入了超过50000英尺（约合15240米）高的
above 50,000 feet.
所谓的“空间等效区域”
But more primarily is what happens to us
但更重要的是当我们到达那个高度
when we go to that height.
我们会怎么样
Our bodies have evolved to process oxygen properly
人类的进化程度让我们可以在
from sea level to 10,000 feet.
从海平面到10000英尺（约合3048米）高处之间正常呼吸
How much is 8 minus 3?
8减3是多少？
8 minus 3 is 4.
8减3等于4
When we go above that,
当我们处于这个高度之上时
we cease being able to functionally take in oxygen.
我们就难以正常吸入氧气
Put up the switches or you will die.
Man:打开开关 不然你会死
Put up the switches.
打开开关！
[ Radio chatter, static ]
Therefore, the suit and the cabin of the plane
因此 增压服和机舱
have to artificially induce
必须人为地增加
the conditions of atmospheric pressure
空气压力
in order so that the pilots stay alive.
来保证飞行员的生命安全
That is a significant amount of technology
这是一项可以解决这个问题的
to solve that one problem.
意义重大的技术
Just pull down on the red lanyard...
只要拉下红色的系索
It potentially could whack you on the face...
它可能会打到你的脸
It releases a hook on the inside of your harness.
它会在你的增压服内侧放出一个钩子
After a full day
Narrator:在整整一天的
of intense information acquisition...
紧张的学习之后
Day 3 dawns and our raw recruits...
第三天来临了 我们的菜鸟新兵
Time to start training.
训练时间到
...Are getting physical.
开始了体能训练
Wanna see the coolest part? Ha ha, look at that! Badge.
想看看最酷的东西吗？hhh看这个！徽章！
With a crash course in what to do
在撞击课程中——当飞机坠毁时
if the plane crashes.
应该如何应对
That's three weeks of army airborne
这是军队里三个星期的空降
and parachute training right there.
和伞降训练
That's all you do.
这是你全部的训练内容
Land!
跳！
This is pretty cool.
这真是极好的
We've just gotten walked through
我们刚刚经历了
all of the different contingencies that could happen
如果必须在高空弹射出飞机时
if we have to bail out of the plane at altitude.
所有可能出现的紧急情况
This is very cool.
酷毙了
What happens when the parachute lands, how to land.
伞降时会发生什么 如何着陆
It's easy to land like so.
像这样着陆十分容易
Gonna break -- something's broken.
会坏掉……有些地方会摔伤
Fascinating.
太有趣了
And most specifically...
最特别的是
There we are.
来吧
[ Chuckles ]
I just learned how to actually lower myself
我刚刚学会了 当我的降落伞被树挂住
if I end up landing in a tree
我被吊在半空时
and I'm, like, hanging above the ground.
该如何放低自己
[ Groans ]
Ah ha, there we go.
啊哈，来吧
And then lowering myself safely down to the ground.
然后让降低我的高度自己安全地落到地面
Lower myself down.
降低我的高度
[ Rope whirs ] Very nice.
[ Rope whirs ] 灰常棒
All of this is stuff that I hope I only ever have to try
我希望所有这些技巧只需要在
here in the safety of this room.
这间安全的房子里用到
It's been a long and exhausting day.
真是漫长而疲劳的一天
Bail out, bail out, bail out.
弹出 弹出 弹出
And the sheer scale of the task, technology,
这场测试的绝对规模，科技
and expertise required to fly at the edge of space,
和在太空边缘飞行所需的专业姿势
could not be more apparent.
是显而易见的
Two words come to mind during all this --
两个词蹦到我的脑子里面
complex and terrifying.
错综复杂 胆战心惊
Three days of information overload...
三天的信息过载之后
The ejection seat we have was also used in the first
我们所使用的紧急弹射装置
four flights of the space shuttle Columbia.
也在哥伦比亚号航天飞机的前四次飞行中使用
Narrator:...And the rigors of flying the Dragon Lady
Narrator:并且驾驶蛟龙夫人的困难
are evident.
也显现出来了
But is it the hardest plane to pilot?
但它真的是最难驾驶的飞机吗？
To find out, the Mythbusters are being prepped to fly
为了搞清这个问题 流言终结者们已经准备好
to the edge of space.
在太空边缘飞行了
These are like my space jammies.
就像我的太空睡衣
And despite the high spirits...
尽管士气高涨
[ Woman chuckles ]
All right, sir, can you hear me?
好了 先生 你能听到我吗
Yep, I kind of  feel like dancing.
能 我现在感觉想要跳舞
Narrator:...The pressure is on, literally.
Narrator:开始增压了，真的
All right, bring your... [ Speaks indistinctly ]
好了 拿来……[ Speaks indistinctly ]
Jamie and Adam have one final stage of training
杰米和亚当还需通过最后一个训练阶段
to be passed as fit to fly.
就可以准备飞行了
Oh. You doing okay?
哦♂~
你还好吗
That's different. [ Chuckles ]
非一般的感觉 [ Chuckles ]
In fact,  that doesn't feel very good.
事实上 感觉并不怎么样
[ Air hisses ]
Ow. Gonna bring you back down.
嗷w
我会降低压力
I could see somebody feeling like panicking.
It's just, that's a lot of stuff to process.
这只是……有很多东西要处理
They each have a full systems check
他们每人都要在增压服内
in the pressure suit,
进行一次全系统的检查
followed by a high-altitude emergency simulation.
接下来就是高空紧急情况模拟
Right now Jamie is getting fitted
现在杰米被塞进了这个
into this high-altitude pressure chamber.
高空气压模拟室
Right and left gloves are integrated and locked.
左右手套都连接好并且锁死了
It will replicate the lack of pressures
它在那套增压服内会模拟
that he might experience under different circumstances
在不同环境下可能会遇到的
in that very suit.
失压状况
The environment inside the chamber
模拟室里面的环境
will simulate the flight plan of a u-2.
会模拟u-2的飞行计划
So, Jamie, what we're gonna do now
那么 杰米 我们现在就要
is bring the chamber up to 5,000 feet,
模拟5000英尺（1524米）高处的气压
check the ears and sinuses and make sure they're clearing okay.
检查耳鼻 确保他们没事
If the cabin pressure of the u-2 was to fail...
如果u-2机舱内的气压开始降低
How you feelin' right now?
你现在感觉怎么样？
I feel fine.
我没事
Narrator:...Jamie needs to prove he can operate the suit
Narrator:杰米需要证明他可以操作这套增压服
and emergency systems.
以及紧急系统
So right now we're just doing a slow ascent up to, uh,
那么我们现在缓慢上升到 呃
flight level 4-0-0.
飞行高度层 4-0-0
As they approach cruising altitude,
当接近巡航高度的气压时
there's a startling reminder of the dangers involved.
一个惊人的事实揭示了其中的危险
Oh, there we go.
噢，出现了
A breaker of water at body temperature
水在体温环境下
begins to boil.
突然开始沸腾
If Jamie's suit were to fail,
如果杰米的增压服失去作用
that's what the liquids in his body would do.
他的体液也会像那杯水一样沸腾
All right, let's go ahead and try to reach that
好我们继续
ejection handle.
试着去够紧急弹射手柄
With that thought in mind,
在最大高度下
and at maximum altitude,
失压的危险时刻在杰米脑中回放
Jamie has a few tasks to complete.
他要完成几个任务
Down by your right buttocks there,
在你的右臀下面
that's the scramble handle.
是应急手柄
Pull it up towards your chin just a little bit. That's good.
把它向上拉一点 很好
The final being the suits automated response
最后的测试是增压服在机舱紧急失压情况下的
to a sudden cabin pressure failure.
自动响应
3...2...1...
And go ahead and pull that helmet hold down.
继续 拉下头盔控制阀
[ Clicking sound ]
That was something else.
这非同一般
It's, uh, it's kind of scary, actually.
呃 事实上 有点害怕
1...
There's a lot of force, and when they, uh,
有很大压力 然后当他们 呃
decompressed rapidly, it's just like, whoa.
突然释放压力时 就像 whoa~
You're sort of feeling like popcorn. [ Chuckles ]
感觉自己就想爆米花 [ Chuckles ]
While Jamie clearly didn't enjoy the experience,
杰米很明显并不享受他的旅程
he did pass muster.
但他确实通过了测试
[ Chuckles ] Oh, awesome.
[ Chuckles ]oh 棒哭了
Cue fanboy savage.
萨维奇小子也跃跃欲试
[ Singsongy ] Oh, the gloves!
[ Singsongy ] 噢~手套们♬~
The coolest thing about this is, I'm not just wearing a suit.
最酷的是 我穿的不仅仅是一套衣服
I'm not even wearing a machine.
甚至也不是机器
Wow!
Oh, man. That's far out.
天啊 好爽
[ Air hisses ]
Whoo!
I'm wearing the apex of decades of tens of thousands
我穿着的是几十年来成百上千人
of people problem solving how to survive in hostile conditions,
在解决极端条件下生存问题上的顶尖成果
and I can feel that technology.
我能感受到科技的力量
Whoa! [ Laughs ]
I can feel how reliable they've made things
我也感觉到他们造的这些东西
to touch and understand with your hands.
在手边操纵起来多么稳妥可靠
All of this borne by hard experience.
这源自艰苦的实验
Lots of people gave their lives
许多人为此牺牲
so that this suit could protect these pilots.
这些增压服才能够保全飞行员的生命
Are you good to go?
你准备好了吗
I am good to go.
准备好了
Honestly, everything about this kind of astounds me
实话说，他们每一天都这样做
that people do this every single day.
才是真正使我震惊的地方
Starting climber 5,000 feet at 5,000 feet coming up.
5000英尺气压准备 5000英尺气压开始
It takes a team of people
有一队人马
to put me in this suit correctly.
帮我穿上这套增压服
How's your comfort level?
你的舒适度怎如何？
Well, I'm farting up a storm.
呃 我的菊花正在酝酿一场风暴
But more than that,
不仅如此
once I was under the simulated depressurization...
我在失压模拟的时候
Oh, there we go. Wow.
哦 开始了 Wow.
...where the suit would inflate, it gets incredibly tiring.
增压服膨胀时 感到十分紧张
Locate the ejection handle in between your legs.
找到你两腿间的紧急弹射手柄
Oh, there you go, sir, your fingers around it.
就在那 先生 你的手指旁边
Yeah, there we go. Okay.
就是这样 不错
These guys have to be in incredible shape
这些飞行员一定有惊人的体能
because I was just sitting in a chair being tested.
我只是坐在椅子上接受测试
These guys are actually potentially flying planes
而他们可能要在这种情况下
under these conditions.
操纵飞机
3...2...1...
[ Clicking sound ]
[ Air whooshes ]
Go ahead and pull that green lanyard.
继续 拉下绿色的系索
Use the mirror.
借助那个镜子
So, our training is done and we are ready to fly.
我们的训练结束了 准备起飞
Excellent. Welcome. Welcome, everyone. [ Chuckles ]
很好 欢迎 欢迎各位 [ Chuckles ]
Remember, we went through all of that
记住 我们通过的那些测试
just to be passengers on the u-2.
只是为了成为u-2的 乘客
Now, we gotta do two things -- one, we gotta figure out
现在还剩下两件事 第一 我们要决定
which one of us is gonna fly, me or Jamie.
哪一个将真正登上飞机 是我还是杰米
And two, we gotta let these professionals figure out
第二 那些专家们要做好
the logistics of their flight plan.
飞行计划的后勤任务
Just a little bit of waiting.
广告之后 马上回来
While Adam and Jamie wait for flight clearance,
在亚当和杰米等待航班的时候
the guys decamp to the perfect location
二人组来到了完全无风的
for wind-protected precision flying.
进行精密飞行测试的完美地点
We are testing the myth that multi-roters
我们在测试多旋翼飞行器
can possibly be lethal.
是否可能致死的流言
So, this is our multi-roter.
嗯 这是我们的飞机
This is our multi-roter pilot James Franklin hyneman.
这是飞行员詹姆斯·富兰克林·海纳曼
And this is our potential victim
这是潜在受害人
with veins filled with blue blood --
他的静脉中流淌着蓝色的血液
clearly a vulcan who we're going to steer
我们就是要让这个玩意
this thing right into.
飞向这个火神
You ready to fly? Sure.
准备好了吗
当然
Okay, here we go. All right.
好 开始吧
[ Drone blades whirring ]
For this first test,
在第一次测试中
we're gonna get our little copter up about this high.
我们要让小飞机飞到这个高度
I wouldn't want this thing flying at me.
我可不想让它冲着我来
Sounds like a swarm of angry bees.
听起来像一群愤怒的蜜蜂
And then drive it right into the neck of our dummy.
然后把它飞向假人的脖子
And we'll see what happens at that speed
看看在这种速度下 使用这样的螺旋桨
with those propellers.
会发生什么
Oh! [ Laughs ]
That was a perfect hit!
完美一击
And it was going pretty quick.
好快啊
[ Beep ] Oh!
It doesn't seem to me that anything at all
在我看来 假人的脖子
happened to the neck.
并未受到什么损害
Take a look at the high speed footage of the multi-roter
看看高速摄像机拍下的
hitting the neck.
飞行器撞击颈部的镜头
You can see the props bending right out of the way
你可以看到 即使是颈部这样柔软的表面
even in the face of something as soft as neck flesh.
螺旋桨也立刻弯到了一边
Yeah, clearly, they were designed to do that.
是啊，很明显它们是这样设计的
Yep, the fly-it-out-of-the-box
Narrator:好吧 在这次飞行中
quad-copter didn't make a dent.
四旋翼飞行器甚至不能打出一点痕迹
But next up, the kid model.
但下一个 就是小模型了
Aha.
啊
That one's much scarier.
妈妈我好怕怕
More likely to be used for large deliveries,
更多地在较大的场合中使用
it's heavier, has more power, 6 roters,
它更重，动力更强，有6个旋翼
and sturdier propellers.
以及更坚固的螺旋桨
Let's see what it can do.
看看它的表现如何
Oh!
哦！
Oop. That's no good.
噢 不太妙
Uh, take two?
呃 再来？
It's going right for me.
直冲 我来了
Oh! Oh!
哦~！哦♂
Oh!
哦♂♂
哦♂♂♂
[ Laughs ] Sorry about that.
[ Laughs ] 我很抱歉
I'd rather not experiment on each other.
我宁愿不这么测试
The larger model is proving trickier to handle.
大一些的飞机更难操控
Aw. Oh.
啊~噢
But eventually,
但最终
Jamie gets it going where he wants it.
杰米得到了它想要的结果
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
耶耶耶耶耶！
Oh, nice!
Oh 厉害啊
Well, bigger multi-roter, bigger propellers,
好吧 更大的飞行器 更大的螺旋桨
nice fat hit right here in the vein, nothing.
颈静脉上的完美一击 却什么都没发生
No penetration.
都没有渗出来
I have to say that,
我得说
aside from being amazing pieces of technology,
除了惊人的科技成果
these multi-roters are genuinely spooky to be around.
这些小飞机飞起来真的像幽灵一样
One, they sound like a hive of angry bees.
第一 它听起来像是一窝嗡嗡直叫的蜜蜂
[ Drone blades whirring ] Oh!
[ Drone blades whirring ] 哦！
Two, I am genuinely physically afraid of them hitting me.
第二 我真的很害怕那些东西会打到我
But apparently, that fear is without any reason,
不过很明显 没有必要恐惧
because we've been smacking them into our neck
因为无论如何我们已经被它们打过了
without any injury whatsoever.
并且没有受到任何伤害
So where does that leave us?
所以我们接下来做什么
Come on. We're the Mythbusters.
来吧 我们可是流言终结者啊
We're gonna sling our camera platform into it.
我们要把我们的相机平台挂载在上面
This has 8 roters, weighs 16 pounds,
它有8个轴 重16磅
and the propellers are not made of plastic
这些扇叶并不是塑料制成的
that bends out of the way.
它们与之恰恰相反
No, they're made of carbon fiber.
它们由碳纤维制成
I'm genuinely scared about what this is gonna do
真的 我很害怕它会对假人的脖子
to this neck.
做什么
Scared and hopeful.
害怕 但又充满希望
The myth that one of these can cause a lethal injury,
这个流言其中之一是说它可以导致致命伤害
is looking suspect.
目前看起来不靠谱啊
He's totally fine.
他的状况看起来很好
But the team is dumping the two
realistic mid-range models...
And going for broke with the "Mythbusters" own
custom-made camera carrying behemoth.
[ Loudly ] I thought the other two multi-roters were scary.
Cue the team's expert pilot, Duncan,
and this myth's final chance for gory glory.
I was wrong. That thing is terrifying.
This large multi-roter is a different beast
than what we've been handling earlier.
All right, shall we do this?
You ready? Ready.
It's much bigger and heavier.
Once it starts to move into the neck,
it doesn't wanna just bounce off
because it's so heavy.
So, I think this is gonna actually do something
to our neck,
something bad.
Yes!
[ Laughs ] Look at that!
It's bleeding.
That's bad! [ Laughs ]
Dude!
Yes!
There you have it, kids.
It's all fun and games until someone loses an eye,
or a vein.
You put your finger there, you'll be fine.
I'm not sure.
So what have we proven after all this mayhem?
I think we've actually proven two different things.
On one hand, the smaller multi-roters
you can buy at the store are pretty darn safe
and they're designed to be that way.
But this is a new hobby, and there are lots of people
building larger and larger multi-roters
to handle bigger and bigger payloads.
And when those multi-roters get bigger,
the dangers they present are absolutely real.
I know we've been looking at a worst-case scenario,
but I think we've gotta call this thing plausible.
Do you agree?
I agree, you know, as a general rule,
I always try not to put my neck
near large, heavy, fast-moving objects
with spinning blades on them.
I think that's a good general rule.
Let's get out of here. [ Chuckles ]
4...3... Let it down a little...
指挥员: 4...3... 稍微下降一点
Back at beale,
回到beale
the guys are ready to carry out the final test
二人已经准备好对这则流言
on the mythically- difficult-to-fly u-2.
进行最终测试
But only one of them gets to go.
但他们中只有一个人能上
Well... [ sighs ] You know, for crying out loud,
内个... [ sighs ] 你知道, for crying out loud,
you're -- you're a fanatic about this stuff.
你对这种事情非常狂热
You collect these things. Yeah, I do.
你搜集这些东西 是的
And so, I can't in good conscience deny you
所以 我大发慈悲地
the, uh, the pleasure of doing something like that.
不去否定你和你做这些事情的乐趣
I really appreciate that, sir. Thank you very much.
我真的很感激 谢谢你
You owe me one. Oh, I totally owe you one.
算你欠我一个人情 Oh, 我绝对欠你一个人去
[ Chuckles ] Absolutely.
真的
[ Under breath ] Yeah! Wah!
Yeah! Wah!
Jamie the gentleman steps down.
绅士杰米下岗
A very happy Adam steps up.
巨爽亚当上岗
I'm pretty excited. Can you tell?
我好兴奋啊！你看得出吗
...For the defining, not quite hands-on test.
Now it's go time to figure out just how hard this plane
现在是时候 去看看这架飞机
will be to fly.
究竟多难飞
I won't be flying it, no, no, no.
我不会驾驶这架飞机
I'll just be helping to assess that.
我只是帮助评估
It is an unbelievable day here in northern California.
这是难以置信的一天 在北加利福利亚这里
There is barely a cloud in the sky.
天上几乎没有云
It's incredibly clear.
晴空万里
It is a perfect day for flying.
在今天飞行再好不过
So, Adam, the engine's starting to spool up.
好了, 亚当引擎启动了
Oh, yeah.
Once that's happened and we have sufficient r.P.M.,
当它达到一定转速
I'll add a little bit of, uh, jet fuel here.
我就会喷点油进去
Okay, here we go, folks.
大伙儿我们要出发了
Adam's gotta be freaking out about now.
亚当现在肯定被吓尿了
[ Plane engine roaring ]
[ 引擎咆哮 ]
All right, Adam, at this point you need to make sure
好的亚当,
that the boost lever is aft and your t-block there
现在你要确认一下增压操纵杆是否打到aft档
under your left rib cage is one notch open.
还要确认在你左肋下的t-block有无打开的缺口
Yes, it is currently one notch open.
现在没有打开的缺口
Boost lever's still aft.
增压操纵杆也在aft档
[ Radio chatter ]
I tell you one thing, this plane is such a unique
我话你听 这架飞机飞起来
and problematic thing to fly
既独一无二又困难重重
that it requires a lot of people to make sure
这需要一堆人在起飞前
it's all perfect before it takes off.
保障你的飞机一切正常
All right, the pogo crew has pulled the pin
好的 辅助轮人员已经拔出了辅助轮的插销
so the pogos will fall away as we take off.
因此当我们起飞时 辅助轮就会脱落了
[ Radio chatter ]
All the checklists have been checked.
检查单完成
We are just seconds away from taking off.
我们离起飞仅剩数秒
[ Radio chatter ]
All right, here we go, break release, full power.
好的 我们起飞 释放刹车 推满油门！
[ Roaring ]
[ 引擎咆哮 ]
Here we go.
嘿喂狗
Here we go. We are taking off.
我们正在起飞
Oh, man.
哦天啊
That is a lot of horsepower.
这马力得多强啊
That's a -- wow! We're already lifting!
这是 wow 我们正在升空！
That's crazy!
碉堡了
Whoa!
Wow!
Man, that's steep.
woc爬升得真快
Wow! We are already lifting. We're banking hard to the right.
Wow!我们已经升空了 而且正向右滚转
This is part of a, uh,
take off that keeps the u-2 above the base.
We're sort of spiraling straight up.
我们正不断爬升
Holy cow.
哇塞
That was so fast!
这真的太快了
[ Laughs ]
We're turning on a dime as we spiral up into the air,
在爬升的同时
climbing very rapidly.
我们还在作小半径转弯
After a tricky takeoff,
在tricky的起飞
and rapid initial ascent...
和疾速爬升后
Oh, my God, the view is beautiful!
我的天这太美了
Major Bartholomew and Adam get a chance
巴瑟缪罗上校和亚当
to sit back and relax.
终于可以坐和放宽了
Right now we just passed the top of mount Everest.
我们正在超过珠穆朗玛峰的高度
Until they attain cruising altitude.
直到他们达到巡航高度
We're transitioning now from 160-knot climb to a, uh,
我们正在从以160节爬升的状态
.715 mach cruise.
转入0.715马赫的巡航
Three-quarters of the speed of sound.
也就是音速的四分之三
This is officially the highest off the ground I have ever been.
这就是我到过的最高的地方了
We are coming up on 60,000 feet,
我们正在接近60000英尺
12 Miles above the surface of the earth.
距地面12英里
And the sky has gotten to be a very, very dark blue.
天空变成了非常非常暗的蓝色
What an unbelievably beautiful day.
这真是难以置信美的一天
And from this height, 67,500 feet...
到了67500英尺这个高度
[ Inhales deeply ]
The edge of our planet has a definitive curve to it.
就能看到我们地球的弧线了
It is, uh, more three dimensional
这比我曾经见到的
than I have ever seen it.
更加真实
[ Inhales deeply, exhales slowly ]
There we are.
我们到了
Ladies and gentlemen, 70,000 feet.
女士们绅士们 7w英尺
[ Inhales deeply, exhales slowly ]
At this point,
在这里
aside from the six astronauts on the space station,
除了空间站里的6名宇航员
we are the two highest humans off of planet earth.
我们是地球上最高的两个人了（其实你更高一点）
More than double the height
比普通商业航班
of a standard commercial airliner.
飞行高度的两倍还高
Ha, and did I mention
蛤 我有没提到我还穿着
I'm wearing a pressurized space suit? Yeah.
一件增压宇航服
Strapped to a rocket.
被绑在一支火箭上
This is not a bad way to spend your day.
以这样的方式度过一天还是蛮爽的
Jamie, I totally owe you one.
杰米 我真的欠你一个人情
The complex, exhaustive preparations
复杂又繁琐的准备
and taxing takeoff seem a world away.
和费力的起飞 似乎都烟消云散了
Oh, look at that.
哦 看那
Wow. That is San Francisco. That's my home.
Wow. 那是旧金山 那是我的家
But this is exactly what the u-2 is designed to do,
但这就是U-2的设计目的
spend hours up here looking down,
在这待上几个小时 往下看
gathering intelligence.
搜集情报
The view from a commercial airliner is beautiful.
如果说商业航班上的景色很美
This one is transcendent.
那么这里的景色就是无与伦比的
It's the maneuvers at either end of proceedings
where the pilots earn the big bucks.
The challenges in landing this plane are unique.
降落这架飞机的挑战是独一无二的
And Adam is about to get a real close look.
而亚当即将要近距离体验
We'll be back with our landing after this commercial break.
广告之后我们即将着陆
[ Laughing ]
Hey, space boy, how you doin' up there?
嘿 太空男孩 你在上面还好吧
I'm doin' pretty good, Jamie.
好的不得了 杰米
The view up here is absolutely astonishing.
这里的景色无疑是惊人的
Looking at it makes you realize that...
看到这种景象 我想到
You've left the bulk of the earth's atmosphere.
天空是幽暗的
That's why it's dark.
因为你已经飞出了大气层的主体
You're looking down at this fragile mist
你可以俯瞰这层薄雾
that surrounds our...
环绕着
Our globe that allows us to breathe.
我们的地球 让我们自由呼吸
What allows me to do so is the ingenuity
我能这么做 全靠成千上万人辛勤工作
of thousands and thousands of hardworking men and women
得到的精巧设计
who have sought to harness the raw materials
他们将地里挖出来的东西
that we dig out of the ground into things as astonishing
变为奇迹
as airplanes and pressure suits.
飞机如此 增压服亦如此
[ Inhales deeply, exhales slowly ]
What a privilege.
荣幸至极
Oh, man. That is a lot of horsepower.
Wow, we're already lifting. That's crazy!
Whoa! Wow!
Oh, my God, the view is beautiful.
Wow, look at that.
There's no doubt the high-altitude u-2
毋庸置疑 U-2这款高空侦察机
is a beautiful piece of aviation technology.
是航空技术的杰作
Captain needed apple pie.
机长需要苹果派
Yeah.
But the question yet to be answered is...
但问题是
Oh, that's delicious.
好餈
...Is it the most difficult to fly and land?
这是最难飞的飞机吗
These guys fly these planes
这些人开着这种飞机
upwards of 12 to 14 hours at a time. Mmm.
每次超过12到14小时 Mmm好餈
Yep, and after such mammoth flight times...
恩 而在这艰巨的飞行之后
You must have some butt shimmying exercises
you do to keep yourself from going numb during long flights.
来防止你发麻
I call it building your ass-callus.
我把它称作 构建屁股的愈伤组织
[ Adam laughs ]
...Comes the landing.
该降落了
All righty, ready to begin the descent.
好的 准备下高
This is where the rubber meets the runway.
这就是橡胶遇见跑道的地方
Gonna start by dropping the gears.
准备打开起落架
So you'll feel a little bit of a clunk.
所以你可能会听到一些闷响
And perhaps the biggest challenge
也可能是对所有飞行员
facing any pilot anywhere.
最大的挑战
Two gear down and locked.
两起落架落下并锁住
Now I'm gonna bring the throttle back.
现在开始收油门
The Dragon Lady lands tail-wheel first
蛟龙夫人着陆时后轮先触地
at a speed that practically stalls the wing.
实际上这时记忆已经失速
And with only two sets of landing gear
这就像降落一辆自行车
in the center of the fuselage, it's like landing a bicycle.
因为只有机身中间的两组起落架
The pilot has floored the landing gear
飞行员已经放下了起落架
and implemented several procedures to add drag
并且通过一些措施增加了阻力
so that it's moving slow enough when we get to the runway,
所以当我们到达跑道时 她就足够慢了
then we can actually land.
然后我们就可以着陆了
That's not all. There's the ground effect.
但这还没完 还有地面效应
The u-2's high-aspect ratio wings and commensurate uplift
U-2的大展弦比机翼和与之相称的高升力
means that on final approach, it tends to float,
意味着在最终进近时 她会发飘
requiring incredible skill to control.
需要不可思议的技巧来控制
There's also the issue of runway visibility.
而且还有视野问题
This is the chase car and it's being driven by
这是追逐车
an actual u-2 pilot.
由真正的U-2飞行员驾驶
Because the pilot in the plane has such limited visibility
因为飞机里的飞行员只有有限的视野
that he can't even see the runway
他们甚至看不见跑道
when he's down close to it.
当他接近跑道时
This pilot is gonna be talking him down
车里的飞行员就会一英尺一英尺引导他
with foot-by-foot instructions so that he can respond
让他在正确的时间 正确的地点
appropriately at the right time.
作出正确的反应
Bartholomew: And we're on our threshold speed.
我们正处于临界速度
[ Speaking indistinctly ]
高度2300 航向207
And now this is the fun part.
现在到了有趣的部分了
This is the part where I earn the big u-2 pilot bonus money.
就是这部分让我赚到U-2飞行员奖金
All right, so we have one guy rolling in on final ahead of us.
好的 有个家伙在我们前面进入了跑道
[ Car engine revs ]
Yee-haw.
We are geared down, flaps full, speed brakes out,
起落架放下 襟翼全开 减速板打开
[ speaks indistinctly ] Lights on,
灯光打开
and spoilers in the landing position.
扰流板预位
Configured and ready for landing.
设定完毕 准备着陆
[ Radio chatter ]
Look at that.
看那
15...12...
指挥员：15...12...
10...8...
7...6...5...4...3... Let it down a little at 4.
7...6...5...4...3...稍微压下杆...4.
3, 2, hold it at 1 inches.
3, 2, 稳住 1英尺
Oh... [ chuckles ] [ Chuckles ]
[ Beeping ]
[ Monitor beeping rapidly ] Wow.
Very nice. Welcome back, gentlemen.
指挥员：漂亮 欢迎回来 绅士们
He's required by tradition to say "very nice"
根据传统 不管落得怎样
whether it is or not. Oh, okay.
他都得说很漂亮 Oh, okay.
It's been a lot of fun. Thanks, Adam.
这段旅程非常愉快 谢谢你 亚当
And there's our big old reception committee.
那是我们古老的欢迎委员会
All right, throttle off.
好的 关车
All right, editors,
好的 编辑们
if you could give us a little montage
如果你能给我们在流言终结者里
of some of the astonishing things we've gotten to do
做过的惊人的事
in the course of doing "Mythbusters"...
来个蒙太奇
Welcome back.
欢迎回来
I'm thinking, flying a rocket car across the desert.
我在想 在沙漠里飞一辆火箭车
Watching the rocket sled accelerate to the speed of sound
看着火箭滑橇超过音速
and hit the immovable wall.
然后撞上一堵不动墙
[ Explosion ]
That was awesome! [ Laughter ]
我巨爽
Sliding down a 200-foot water slide
滑下200英尺的水梯
at 70 feet through the air into a target.
飞上70英尺的空中 然后落入一个目标
Aw, yeah! He was like, come on!
[ Applause ] Cheers!
This tops all of those by a factor of two.
因为两个原因 这次的体验冠绝于他们
That was unbelievable.
难以置信
Unrepeatable.
难以重复
Incredible.
不可思议
I'm out of superlatives.
I have just spent the last two hours strapped to a rocket,
我刚被绑在火箭上两个小时
wearing a space suit,
穿着一件太空服
flying to the edge of our earth's atmosphere,
飞到了大气层的边界
and seeing my hometown from a vantage point...
在一个有利位置看我的家乡
Wow!
Bartholomew: That's a great view of the bridge.
这是个看桥的好位置
It is an incredible view.
这是不可思议的景色
...that was completely unique.
完全独一无二
So, Adam, how do you figure we're gonna call this?
所以 亚当 你怎么看
Because, I mean, this is supposed to be
因为 我的意思是 这被期望为
the most difficult plane to fly,
最难飞的飞机
but we haven't looked at any other planes.
但我们还没见过其他飞机
Okay, but we did learn this,
好吧 但我们见识了这架
it is a completely unique airframe purpose-built
这是一架专为特殊任务设计的
for a completely unique mission.
特殊机体
It requires a more numerous flight crew
它比其他飞机
and a more exhausted set of protocols
更多的机组人员
than any other plane in the military.
和更繁琐的协议
And it is the only airborne endeavor
而这也是唯一要求飞行员
besides going to space that requires
除了宇航员
the wearing of the space suit.
穿宇航服
This is not a bad way to spend your day.
I think that places it in the plausible category.
我认为应该把它归入有此可能
Okay. All right.
好的
I think it also places it in the "ultra cool" category.
我觉得还应该把它归入“狂拽炫酷屌炸天”的一类
Absolutely. Let's get out of here.
那当然 我们走吧
So, Adam, do you know why she's called "the Dragon Lady"?
亚当 你知道她为啥被称为蛟龙夫人吗
No, I don't.
不知道呢
'Cause you don't know whether she's gonna land like a dragon
因为你不知道她降落起来像只蛟龙
or a lady. [ Laughs ]
还是像个夫人